Doctor Who (1963) 04x09  The Evil of the Daleks (Episode 5)
《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集 《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第五部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
Sincro: wyxchari
(Jamie and Kemmel are on the minstrels' gallery.)
(They stare down at a Dalek emerging into the chamber beneath them.)
JAMIE: Miss Waterfield? Can you open the door? We've come to get you.
Waterfield 小姐吗？你能打开门吗？我们来救你
(Behind them a door is opening.)
(They throw the rope over the Dalek's head and pull.)
JAMIE: Quick, before we see any more of those mechanical beasties.
快点, 一会儿那些机械怪物就来了
(They go through a door and __ it.)
VICTORIA: Kemel, my dear friend!
Kemel, 我亲爱的朋友！
JAMIE: Aye, he's a good friend, right enough, Miss Waterfield.
是的, 他是个不错的朋友, 非常好, Waterfield 小姐
VICTORIA: And you?
你是。。。？
JAMIE: Er... Introductions in a moment, if you please.
First, I'd like to make us a little bit more secure.
呃。。。一会儿再介绍吧, 不过你没意见的话。首先, 我要加强一下我们的安全措施。
JAMIE: Kemel, if we lash this bedstead across the door, it might just hold.
Kemel, 如果我们把床架子拖到门那里横着的话, 可能能挡一阵子
JAMIE: Rope! That's it. We could do with a chest against it,
I'm thinking. Another one on top, eh?
绳子, 对了！我们可以用胸口顶住, 我在想。上面再来一个, 嗯？
JAMIE: Well now, they can't get in and we can't get out.
So, where does that put us?
好了, 他们也进不来, 我们也出不去了。看, 我们现在怎样了？
JAMIE: Oh. Jamie McCrimmon. I, uh... I came to give you this.
哦, 我叫 Jamie McCrimmon, 我。。。我来是把这个给你
(He gives her the handkerchief.)
DOCTOR: Are you sure you won't join me?
你确定不跟我一起喝点吗？
TERRALL: No, I won't. I very rarely touch it.
不, 我不用。我从来不碰那个
DOCTOR: Oh, dear. W... Well, something else, perhaps?
哦, 亲爱的。好吧, 来点别的, 怎样？
TERRALL: No. Thank you.
不了, 谢谢你
DOCTOR: I know - let me ring for some food. Now, do join me?
我知道了 - 我叫人送点食物来。现在, 陪我一下？
TERRALL: No! You seem determined to involve me.
不！看来你铁了心要把我搅和进来
DOCTOR: Yes. I do, don't I?
是的, 我要这样, 不行吗？
TERRALL: This is a large house. I prefer my own company.
这是一座大房子, 我喜欢一个人呆着
DOCTOR: Oh, how very unsociable.
哦, 怎么这么不合群
TERRALL: Yes, possibly. No doubt you will enjoy your libation
in one of the other rooms.
是的, 也许吧。毫无疑问你也可以在其它房间里面享用你的美酒啊
DOCTOR: Liba...? Ah, Oh, no. Thank you.
I'm... I'm perfectly happy here. Thank you. I'm perfectly happy.
美。。？啊, 不, 谢谢你。我在这里挺高兴, 谢谢你, 我非常高兴
(The Doctor is looking at a knife collection on the wall.)
DOCTOR: What an extraordinary collection, isn't it?
这些收藏真是不凡啊, 是不？
DOCTOR: Hmm? Oh, I... I'm so sorry. I, uh... you...
you didn't... You weren't in the mood for talking, were you?
哦, 对不起。我, 噢, 你。。你没有。。你没有心情聊天, 对不？
TERRALL: Shouldn't you be helping Waterfield and Maxtible with their experiment?
你不是应该在帮 Waterfield 和 Maxtible 他们做实验吗？
DOCTOR: He... he... yes, uh... But I thought I'd have a little rest.
Uh... I wanted to talk to you.
他。。。是的。 但我想我得休息一小会儿。呃。。。我想跟你聊聊
TERRALL: About what, pray?
聊什么？
DOCTOR: About you, Mr. Terrall. You interest me.
Uh... Do you know something?
聊聊你, Terrall 先生。你很让我感兴趣。呃。。。你知道些什么吗？
DOCTOR: Ever since I came to this house, I...
This is Circassian, surely...
自从我到这个房子来, 我。。这是索卡西亚人的, 肯定的。。。
（备注: 索卡西亚有时特指西北高加索人,有时泛指俄罗斯人+土耳其人）
TERRALL: Do I know what?
你刚才问, 我知道什么？
DOCTOR: Circassian?
索卡西亚人？
DOCTOR: Ever since I came to this house,
I have never seen you eat or drink anything.
自从我到这个房子来, 我从来你见过你吃点什么喝点什么
DOCTOR: Now, that's curious, isn't it, hmm?
这很奇怪啊, 对不？
TERRALL: I dine alone.
我一个人用餐
DOCTOR: Yes, I'd thought of that, but, uh...
Waterfield has never seen you eat or drink either.
是的, 我也考虑过这个, 但是, 呃。。。Waterfield 也没有见过你吃东西
TERRALL: You, uh... seem to be a devotee of Edgar Allen Poe.
你。。。看来是埃德加-爱伦-坡的爱好者啊
DOCTOR: Oh, do I?
噢, 是吗？
TERRALL: However it...Ah, isn't wise to make assumptions,
不管怎样, 乱作假设都是不明智的,
TERRALL: ...nor to meddle in affairs which are none of your business.
也不应该乱插手别人的事情
DOCTOR: Touche!
说得好!
DOCTOR: Oh, look. A perfectly ordinary sword,
and yet it appears to be magnetic. And see?
噢, 你看, 一把非常普通的剑, 但它似乎带有磁性。
DOCTOR: Directly you let go, it loses its magnetism.
你的手一放开, 它就没有磁性了
DOCTOR: Now, if uh...if I didn't know better, Mr. Terrall,
I'd say that you were full of some sort of electricity.
哈, 如果。。如果不是我早知道的话, Terrall 先生, 我得说你全身充满了某种电能
WATERFIELD: Doctor? Uh... excuse me. You're wanted.
博士？呃。。打扰了, 请过来
DOCTOR: Oh, hmm. Thank you. Excuse me.
哦, 谢谢你, 先走了
TERRALL: Doctor! No doubt you are a keen student of human nature,
but some things are better left alone.
博士！我不怀疑在研究人性方面你是一位勤垦的学生, 但有些事情还是别管为好
DOCTOR: No, Mr. Terrall. I am not a student of human nature.
不, Terrall 先生。我不是人性方面的学生。
DOCTOR: I am a professor of a far wider academy, of which
human nature is merely a part. All forms of life interest me.
我是一位教授, 涉猎非常广泛, 人性只是其中一小部分。所有形式的生命我都有兴趣
DOCTOR: All forms of life interest me.
所有形式的生命我都有兴趣
(The Doctor and Waterfield leave.)
（博士和 Waterfield 离开了）
WATERFIELD: I'm sorry to interrupt you Doctor,
but it's something rather urgent.
很抱歉打断你们, 博士, 但有些事情真的很紧急
（Terrell 因博士的话对自己产生了怀疑, 于是倒了一杯酒, 但怎么也没法送到嘴边。
他的手开始颤抖, 酒杯掉落, 他双眼变得呆滞, 一个声音响起。。。）
Obey, obey, obey!
服从, 服从, 服从！
JAMIE: ...and so the Doctor and I were brought to the house.
。。于是博士和我就被带到了这所房子
VICTORIA: Why did you risk your life to try and rescue me?
你为什么冒着生命危险来救我？
JAMIE: Would you like some more water?
你不想再来一点水吗？
VICTORIA: You are too modest. It was a silly question.
你太谦虚了。这是一个傻问题
JAMIE: Then tell me, how did they come to capture you in the first place?
那告诉我, 他们一开始是怎么抓住你的？
VICTORIA: I don't remember.
And yet, I seem to remember in the back of my mind
我记不起来了, 不过, 好像我的潜意识里面又记得
VICTORIA: Somebody - oh, I can't recall who it was
- telling me to walk. And I obeyed, blindly and without interest.
有一个人 - 噢, 我想不起来是谁了 - 告诉我往前走, 我就听从了, 很盲然
JAMIE: Aye. Uh... you were drugged, maybe?
啊, 你被下药了, 也许？
VICTORIA: I simply don't know.
The only thing I remember is waking up in a bare room
我就是记不得了。我唯一记得事情就是, 一醒过来就在一个空房子里面
VICTORIA: with one of those terrible, terrible things.
旁边还有一个那种很可怕很可怕的东西
JAMIE: Well, what do you remember before that,
]apart from this hazy recollection?
那, 在那之前你还记得什么, 除了这些模糊的部分？
VICTORIA: I was reading in the sitting room, but I couldn't
concentrate, because I was so worried about Papa.
当时我在客厅读书, 但我就是无法集中精神, 因为我很担心我的爸爸
VICTORIA: I think I fell asleep over my book.
我想后来我是在书上面睡着了
JAMIE: You see, how you came under the power of the Daleks is very important.
你看, 你是怎么落入 Daleks 掌控之中的, 这一点很重要
JAMIE: They can't have done as much as they have without some help.
他们不可能没人帮忙就搞定这么多事情
VICTORIA: Help? From somebody in the house?
帮忙? 这房子里面的人帮的?
JAMIE: Yes, from someone who wants their plans to succeed
是的, 某个期望他们的计划成功的人
JAMIE: - someone who drugged you or...
or found a way of putting you under the power of the Daleks.
某个给你下药的人 - 或者是他找到了某种其他方法让你落入 Daleks 的魔爪
VICTORIA: But how? How could it be done without my knowing?
但怎么会呢？我怎么可能都不知道呢？
MAXTIBLE: You are paying attention Mollie?
你注意力集中了吗, Mollie?
MOLLIE: Yes sir.
是的先生
MAXTIBLE: Then keep your eyes fixed on the jewel.
See how the light catches it?
注意看这颗宝石上。看看光是怎么聚焦在它上面的
MAXTIBLE: Every facet sparkles, does it not?
每一个面都在发光, 对不？
MOLLIE: Yes sir.
是的先生
MAXTIBLE: Flashing. Flashing, like a collection of sparks.
闪光, 闪光, 就像一堆火花
MAXTIBLE: But I know you are tired, Mollie.
You are tired, are you not? Tell me.
但我知道你累了, Mollie, 你累了, 对不对？ 告诉我
MOLLIE: I am tired.
我累了
MAXTIBLE: Then close your eyes and sleep.
You need have no fear, my child.
那就闭上眼睛睡觉吧, 你不用害怕, 我的孩子
MAXTIBLE: A deep, heavy sleep. Oh, you are so exhausted.
深深地陷入睡眠, 噢, 你都累坏了
MAXTIBLE: And now, in your sleep, you will hear only my voice.
现在, 在你的睡梦里, 你将只听见我的声音
MOLLIE: Only your voice.
只有您的声音
MAXTIBLE: You have been dreaming, Mollie - dreaming that
there are mysteries in this house - that all is not well.
你一直是在做梦, Mollie, 梦到房子里出现神秘的东西, 那并不是真的
MAXTIBLE: You have dreamt that you heard the voice of Miss Waterfield.
But it was all your imagination.
你梦到过你听到了 Waterfield 小姐的声音, 但那只不过是你是的想象
MAXTIBLE: It was nothing but a dream. Do you understand?
都只不过是一个梦, 你明白吗？
MOLLIE: Nothing but a dream.
只不过是一个梦
MAXTIBLE: That is correct. Now, when I tell you to open your eyes,
you will go back to your room and lie down on your bed.
那就对了。现在, 当我让你睁开眼睛的时候, 你将回到你的房间去, 躺到你的床上
MAXTIBLE: And when you awaken, the dream will fade and you will forget
all your suspicions, for they might be injurious to your health.
你醒来的时候, 梦就会消退, 你就会忘了你所有的怀疑, 因为它们可能对你的健康不利
MAXTIBLE: Now, open your eyes.
现在, 睁开你的眼睛吧
(Mollie leaves the room.)
TERRALL: An excellent subject.
I'd no idea that mesmerism was one of your accomplishments.
漂亮啊, 我没想到你居然擅长催眠术
MAXTIBLE: How else do you suppose that
I persuaded Victoria to go to the Daleks?
否则你以为我是怎么说服 Victoria 跑到 Daleks 那里去的？
TERRALL: I see. What of the experiment?
我明白了。实验怎么样了？
MAXTIBLE: It progresses.
有点进展
TERRALL: Are you sure of the Doctor?
你对博士有信心吗？
MAXTIBLE: No, but he is watched.
没有, 但他被监视着呢
TERRALL: Mmm. And Waterfield?
嗯。 那 Waterfield 呢？
MAXTIBLE: Waterfield's usefulness is nearing it's end.
Your intervention in the stables was untimely.
Waterfield 的用途快结束了。你在马厩的介入真不是时候啊
TERRALL: Maxtible, help me!
Maxtible, 帮帮我!
MAXTIBLE: What do you mean?
什么意思?
TERRALL: I... I seem to be in the grip of something.
我似乎被什么东西控制住了
TERRALL: Sometimes my thoughts are clear; sometimes muddled.
有时候我脑袋挺清醒, 有时候就乱成一团
TERRALL: I... I don't know what's happened. Help me!
我。。。我不知道发生了什么, 帮帮我
MAXTIBLE: I can only help you if you obey me.
你服从于我的话, 我才能帮你
TERRALL: But I obey our masters.
但我服从于我们的主人
MAXTIBLE: I prefer to call them our colleagues.
It is their wish that you should obey me.
我倒是更愿意把他们叫做同事。你服从于我也是他们的愿望
TERRALL: You? But you would have killed Waterfield
if they hadn't made me stop you.
你？但如果不是他们让我阻止你的话, 你都已经杀死 Waterfield 了
MAXTIBLE: A slight misunderstanding on the part of our friends.
But now it is your turn to obey.
我们的朋友有一点误会了。现在轮到你来服从了
(Maxtible presses a button on the wall.)
（Maxtible 按了墙上的一个按钮）
MAXTIBLE: I have a task for you to perform.
我有一个任务需要你去办
MAXTIBLE: This entrance leads to the south wing of my house and to a certain room.
这个入口通道我房子的南厢某个房间
MAXTIBLE: You will fetch Victoria Waterfield and bring her to me.
你要去找到 Victoria , 把她给我带过来
TERRALL: But, Maxtible...
但是, Maxtible...
MAXTIBLE: Do as you are told.
照我吩咐的做
Obey, obey, obey!
服从, 服从, 服从！
MAXTIBLE: Well?
怎样？
TERRALL: I will bring Victoria to you.
我将把 Victoria 给你带过来
(Terrall steps through the panel.)
WATERFIELD: Is it finished?
完成了吗?
DOCTOR: Very nearly. Jamie was magnificent.
But then, I knew he would be.
快了。Jamie 真的很棒。不过呢, 我一早就知道他会的
DOCTOR: He produced a whole battery of emotions;
each one of which is imprinted in here. See?
他产生了一整堆的情绪, 每一种都被记录在这里, 看到了没？
WATERFIELD: The "Human Factor"?
这就是“人类特质”？
DOCTOR: Well, a part of it at least. The... the better part
嗯, 至少也是一部分, 。。。好的那部分
DOCTOR: - courage, pity, chivalry, friendship,
even compassion. Some of the virtues.
勇气、怜悯、冒险、友情, 还有同情心, 都是些美德
WATERFIELD: In there?
都在这里？
DOCTOR: Yes, it's a positronic brain. We're going to implant
one of these into each of these three Daleks here. The dormant ones.
是的, 都在这个正子脑里。我们要把他们植入到这三个 Dalek 里面去, 休眠的这几个
WATERFIELD: So the end is in sight?
这么说眼看就要结束了？
DOCTOR: Perhaps.
很可能
WATERFIELD: What happens when the capsule comes into contact with
the brain of the Dalek and starts to influence it?
当这些胶囊跟 Dalek 的大脑接触之后会发生什么？会开始影响他们吗？
DOCTOR: Perhaps it will drive them insane.
可能会把他们逼疯
WATERFIELD: Or turn them into super-beings?
或者变成超级生物？
DOCTOR: Hmm. Well, that is their purpose.
At least, I imagine it is.
嗯, 是的, 那正是他们的目标。至少, 我觉得是
DOCTOR: I can't help feeling that there's more in this than meets the eye.
我有种感觉, 这里会有些让人难以置信的东西
DALEK: You have completed the experiment?
你已经完成实验了？
DOCTOR: Yes, the three capsules are nearly ready.
是的, 这三个胶囊已经快准备好了
DALEK: Stand in front of the cabinet and speak when you have finished.
你完成之后, 站到柜子前面, 告诉我
DOCTOR: Yes, yes. I understand.
好的, 好的, 我知道了
DALEK: Doctor, be careful.
博士, 小心点
(The Dalek returns to the cabinet.)
WATERFIELD: Doctor?
博士?
DOCTOR: Hmm?
嗯?
WATERFIELD: You can't... you mustn't do it.
你不能。。。你绝对不能干这个
DOCTOR: What do you mean?
你什么意思？
WATERFIELD: You must stop the experiment.
你必须停止这个实验
DOCTOR: Oh, you should have thought of that some time ago.
噢, 你现在才这么想啊
WATERFIELD: I know.
我知道
DOCTOR: It's no use having a conscience now.
这会儿谈良心已经没有用了
WATERFIELD: But... before it's too late...
但是。。。还不算太迟。。。
DOCTOR: It was too late when they took away your daughter.
他们劫走你女儿的时候就已经太迟了
DOCTOR: It was too late when you stole my TARDIS
and lured me to this house and this century.
你偷走我的 TARDIS , 把我骗到这个时间这个地点的时候, 就已经太迟了
WATERFIELD: Yes, but what are we doing? What are we really doing?
Turning these creatures into super-beings.
是, 但我们现在在干什么？到底在干什么？在把这些怪物变成超级生物
DOCTOR: Almost superior, anyway.
的确很高级, 不管怎么说
WATERFIELD: Adding what is best and finest in human nature to
all that is brilliant and superior in them. They'll be unbeatable.
他们已经很聪明很厉害了, 再加上人类最好、最优秀的特质, 他们就是不可战胜的了
DOCTOR: That is their purpose.
这正是他们的目的
WATERFIELD: But you're making over the whole world to them.
但你这是在将整个世界交给他们
WATERFIELD: Don't you realise that? Our world, our future.
They will enslave us for all time.
你还没有意识到吗？我们的世界, 我们的未来。他们会一直奴役我们
DOCTOR: That, Mr. Waterfield, remains to be seen.
那, Waterfield 先生, 拭目以待吧
(The Doctor returns to his work on the capsules.)
(Waterfield picks up a metal bar.)
DOCTOR: Attacking me will do no good.
攻击我不会带来什么好处
DOCTOR: Now, listen. You've done all of this because of your daughter.
现在, 你听着, 你做这一切只是因为你的女儿
DOCTOR: Jamie is with her now and they're both still
in the power of the Daleks. They must be set free!
Jamie 现在跟她在一起, 他们俩都还在 Daleks 的手上, 必须得把他们救出来！
WATERFIELD: And sacrifice a whole world - a history
- past, present and future? Destroy an entire race?
但就要牺牲一整个世界吗？整个历史 - 过去、现在和未来？毁灭整个人类？
DOCTOR: Yes. I... I don't think you quite realise what you're saying.
是的。。我想你并不太明白你在说什么。
DOCTOR: But yes, it may come to that. It may very well come to that.
但是是的, 是可能走到那一步, 非常有可能走到那一步
JAMIE: So, with the Dalek's eye stick pointing forward,
于是, 正当 Dalek 的眼睛朝着前面的时候
JAMIE: Kemel and I were able to tiptoe up behind him,
throw the rope over his head and throw him into the fire.
Kemel 和我蹑手蹑脚走到他的后面, 把绳子扔过他的头, 把他拽到火里去了
VICTORIA: What are they doing?
他们在干什么？
JAMIE: They must be trying to get through.
You'd better stand back, Miss Waterfield.
他们正试图突进来。你最好靠后, Waterfield 小姐
VICTORIA: Why not break the door down? They're strong enough.
为什么不破门而入呢？他们够结实啊
JAMIE: I don't know. Maybe they want us alive. I... I just don't know.
我不知道, 也许他们想抓活的。。我真不知道
(Kemel touches the door.)
JAMIE: Is it hot? Aye, well, there's no smoke.
有点热？哎，还好，没有冒烟
JAMIE: Could be one of their newfangled inventions
trying to melt their way through.
可能是他们在用什么新玩意儿想把门溶掉
JAMIE: Look, you'd better stand right back.
Why didn't they try before this, is what I don't understand.
喏，你最好往后站。为什么他们之前不试这招呢，我有些搞不懂
(They start to pile boxes against the door.)
JAMIE: Anyway, we'll make it as hard for them as we possibly can.
不管怎样，我们已经尽量让他们轻松不了了。
JAMIE: Come on, Kemel. Excuse me. Take this.
That's it. That one too.
快来, Kemel, 抱歉, 拿着这个, 对了, 还有那个
(The wall behind Victoria slides open.)
JAMIE: What's puzzling me is: there were two on the way up here,
and there was a Dalek up here, and you were up...
这有点让我难办了：这条路上有两个 Dalek, 这条路上也有一个, 你又。。。
(Terrall drags Victoria away..)
JAMIE: Hey, Miss Waterfield!
嘿, Waterfield 小姐!
Jamie!
Mmph!
JAMIE: Hey, did you hear it? Of course! Why didn't I use my head?
There's another way in and out of here. Come on!
嘿, 你听到了吗？当然！我怎么这么不用脑子！这里还有一条路出去, 快来！
(Kemel finds the opening and they go through.)
(The barriage(??) begins to collase as the Daleks break in.)
(As Terrall tries to find the opening device in the wall,
she breaks free and runs off.)
JAMIE: Oh, no. Two ways to go. Uh...
Kemel, you go that way. If it's a dead end, follow me.
噢, 不要, 有两条路, 噢。。Kemel, 你去那边, 如果是条死路, 回来跟我走
JAMIE: Right.
对了
JAMIE: Where's Victoria Waterfield?!
Victoria Waterfield 在哪儿？
TERRALL: You'll never find her.
你再也找不到她了
JAMIE: Tell me!
告诉我
RUTH: Mollie, go and fetch the Doctor, quick!
Mollie, 去叫博士来, 快！
MOLLIE: Yes, mistress.
好的, 女主人
RUTH: Hurry! Arthur, stop it. I implore you! Stop it!
快！Arthur, 停下！我求你了, 停下来！
TERRALL: Leave me!
别管我
RUTH: Please, I implore you. Stop it!
我求你了, 停下吧
RUTH: Jamie, what have you done?
Jamie, 你干了什么！
JAMIE: But, I can't understand it. He just... just collapsed.
只是, 我也搞不明白, 他突然。。就瘫倒了
RUTH: Arthur, are you all right? What's happened to him?
Arthur, 你没事吧？他怎么了？
DOCTOR: Do you want to save a man's life?
你想救这个人的命吗？
RUTH: What do you...?
你什么意。。?
DOCTOR: Do you?
想吗？
RUTH: Yes!
是的！
DOCTOR: Then take him away from here, as far away as possible.
Go and get the carriage round to the stables.
那赶快把他带离这里, 有多远走多远。去马厩牵驾马车过来
DOCTOR: You go too Mollie. We'll bring him after you. Now do go along.
你也去, Mollie, 我们带着他随后就来。现在赶紧走
RUTH: But, Doctor.. Oh, Mollie.
但是, 博士。。。噢, Mollie
TERRALL: Ah, ah, ah, ah!
啊, 啊, 啊, 啊！
DOCTOR: Yes, I thought he was under some sort of control. Come along.
是的, 我想他是被什么东西给控制了。快来
TERRALL: The creatures!
是那些怪兽!
DOCTOR: Yes, don't worry about them.
是的, 不用担心他们
TERRALL: There's danger, I tell you. Some kind of danger.
这里有危险, 我跟你说, 某种危险
DOCTOR: Yes, I know there's danger.
You must leave here immediately.
是的, 我知道这里有危险。你们必须马上离开这里
TERRALL: The house... the creatures abroad.
这栋房子。。。怪兽已经来了
DOCTOR: Now you leave them to us. Take Ruth Maxtible with you.
She's waiting for you at the stables.
让我们来对付他们吧。你把Ruth Maxtible 带上, 她在马厩等你呢
TERRALL: Yes, very well.
好吧
JAMIE: Can you manage?
你能行吗？
TERRALL: Yes, I think so. Wait.
There's something in the back of my mind.
嗯, 我觉得还行。等等, 我脑袋里面好像还有件事
TERRALL: Victoria Waterfield -
I feel I've harmed her in some way.
Victoria Waterfield, 我感觉我好像伤害了她
DOCTOR: Victoria is safe and well.
Victoria 现在很安全很好
TERRALL: You... You're positive?
你。。。你确定？
DOCTOR: Yes, I'm positive. Now we'll take care of her.
You must leave immediately.
是的, 我确定。我们会照顾她的。你必须赶紧离开了
TERRALL: Yes, if that's what you want.
I'll find Ruth by the stables?
好, 如果你想要这样。我会在马厩找到 Ruth?
DOCTOR: Yes!
是的！
JAMIE: Well, that's fine for Ruth Maxtible,
but you lied about Victoria.
Ruth Maxtible 倒是没问题了, 但 Victoria 的情况你撒了谎
DOCTOR: Yes Jamie, and we must turn that lie into a truth.
是的 Jamie, 我们必须得把那个谎言变成事实
DALEK: Turn around. Pick up the human female. Obey. Obey!
转过身来, 拾起那个人类女性, 服从！服从！
DALEK: Hurry! Hurry! Move into the cabinet. Obey! Move!
快！快！到柜子里去！服从！走！
DOCTOR: Well Jamie, the experiment's nearly over.
好了 Jamie, 实验基本上结束了
DOCTOR: I've had no sleep. I've been up all night,
but it's been worth it.
我都没有睡觉。我忙了一整夜, 但这是值得的
JAMIE: Ah, don't touch me!
哈, 别碰我！
DOCTOR: Now what's the matter?
怎么啦？
JAMIE: Anyone would think this was a little game.
每个人都以为这是一个游戏
DOCTOR: No. It is not a game.
不, 这不是一个游戏
JAMIE: Of course it isn't, Doctor. People have died.
The Daleks are all over the place, fit to murder the lot of us,
当然不是, 博士。有人死了, 而到处都是 Dalek, 追杀着我们
JAMIE: and all you can say is you've had a good night's work.
而你所能说的就是, 你忙了一整夜
DOCTOR: Jamie.
DOCTOR: No, Doctor. Look, I'm telling you this: you and me
- we're finished. You're just too callous for me.
不, 博士, 听着, 我告诉你: 你跟我 - 我们完了！你太无情了!
JAMIE: You're just too callous for me.
Anything goes by the board - anything at all.
我觉得你太阴险了, 所有事情都是阴谋操作 - 所有事
DOCTOR: That's just not true, Jamie.
I've never held that the end justifies the means.
这话不对, Jamie。我从来不认为只要结果正确就可以不择手段
JAMIE: Ach, words. What do I care about words?
You don't give that much for a living soul except yourself.
啊, 编吧。你到底在乎什么？除了你自己, 你在乎过谁？
DOCTOR: I care about life. I care about human beings.
Do you think I let you go through that Dalek test lightly?
我在乎生命, 我在乎人类。你以为我会轻易地让你经历那些 Dalek 实验?
JAMIE: I don't know. Did you?
Look, Doctor, just whose side are you on?
我不知道, 你有吗？说, 博士, 你到底站在那一边？
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jamie. Uh... They're friends.
没关系的, Jamie。啊。。他们是朋友
JAMIE: Friends?
朋友?
DOCTOR: Now don't get the wrong idea. They are the experiment.
别理解错了, 他们是实验品
DOCTOR: Every feeling, every thought impulse you had
during your attempt to rescue Victoria Waterfield
你试图营救 Victoria Waterfield 过程中的每一种感觉, 每一种冲动
DOCTOR: was recorded and made into a small positronic brain
and added to these Daleks.
都被记录下来, 注入了这个小小的正子脑, 装到这几个 Dalek 上
DOCTOR: The "Human Factor" to add to their own powers
- to triumph over human beings.
这就是想要添加到他们自己力量之上，用来超越了人类的东西 - “人类特质”
JAMIE: Well, how do you know they haven't succeeded?
那么，你怎么知道他们没有成功呢？
DOCTOR: Because human beings, Jamie, no matter how brilliant
they may be, are always within reach of other human beings.
因为不管人类有多聪明, 都还总是在其他人触手可及的范围内
DOCTOR: Now then, it's all right, Jamie. Don't worry.
既然这样，没事的，Jamie，不用担心
JAMIE: H... How do you know you can trust them, Doctor?
你怎么知道可以信任他们，博士？
DOCTOR: What is it? What do you want? Hmm? What are you up to?
Ah! What are you doing?
这是什么？你们想要什么？唔，你们在干什么呢？啊，你们在干什么？
JAMIE: Doctor, where are they taking you?
博士，他们要带你去哪儿？
DOCTOR: Where are you taking me? Jamie! They're taking me for a ride!
你们带我去哪儿？Jamie，他们要带我兜兜风！
DOCTOR: Jamie, they're playing a game. It's a game!
hey're taking me for a ride!
Jamie, 他们在玩游戏。这是个游戏！他们在带我兜风！
DOCTOR: A rather amusing little game, don't you think Jamie?
一个很有意思的小游戏，你不觉得吗 Jamie？